http://www.efomp.org/index.php?r=pages&id=privacy-policy

Contacts
European Training and Education for Medical Physics Experts in Radiology
Other Publications
Newsletters (Archive)
1 Overview
The European Federation of Organisations for Medical Physics (EFOMP) is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy notice explains how EFOMP will use any personal information we collect from you.
2 What Information we collect about you
This section shows groups of people whom we collect information about. It then details (for each group) how we collect your data; what we use your personal information for; the legal basis for processing; how long we keep it; categories of personal data; and who we share your data with.
2.1 EFOMP Membership Applicants (National – Affiliate – Individual Associate - Company membership)
2.1.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about the National Member Organisation/Indiviual Associate/Company Member starting at the point of recruitment where we will collect the data from the NMO//Indiviual Associate/Company Member directly via an application form and supporting documents. You have the opportunity to add to this base data by contacting the EFOMP Secretary General. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.1.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply to us may be used in a number of ways.
2.1.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your personal data under the legitimate interest basis for processing.
2.1.4 Legitimate Interest
Applicants expect this processing to take place so that they can be admitted to Membership.
2.1.5 Data retention period
We will keep electronic copies of your application form, while you remain an EFOMP member plus 2 years; or if you are not successful for a period of 2 years.
In addition we will keep a record of the NMO/Company details, membership and financial history on the EFOMP database while you remain an EFOMP member; until we have no longer a legal basis for processing this data.
2.1.6 Categories of personal data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name of the NMO president, vice president, secretary general, treasurer and EFOMP delegates
Name of the Company responsible
Name of the Individual Associate Member
Work/home Email Address
Name of the NMO/Company
Home/work/office Address
Professional Information
Membership Information
Membership Application Form & Supporting Documents
2.1.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.1.7.1 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT providers and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.2 National Member Organisations/Individual Associate Members/Companies
2.2.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point of recruitment where we will collect the data from you directly via an application form and supporting documents. You have the opportunity to add to this base data by contacting the EFOMP Secretary General. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.2.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply to us may be used in a number of ways
To administer your membership.
To administer the annual renewal of the membership
To send you the EFOMP newsletter, EFOMP protocols and policy statements
To send you details of meetings, conferences, events , EFOMP School for Medical Physics Experts editions (ESMPE), and EFOMP examinations (EEB) that we think you may be interested in.
To send you details of services that we think you may be interested in.
To send you details of committees, working groups, special interest groups, networks that you may be interested in
To contact you about and administer complaints.
To provide anonymised workforce data to government and other policy makers.
2.2.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your personal data, with the exception of financial information under the legitimate interest basis for processing. Financial information is processed under the legal basis for processing.
2.2.4 Legitimate Interest
Members expect this processing to take place so that they can receive the published membership benefits.
2.2.5 Data retention period
We will keep electronic copies of your application form, while you remain an EFOMP member plus 2 years. In addition we will keep a record of your personal details, membership and financial history on our database while you remain an EFOMP member; until we have no longer a legal basis for processing this data.
We will keep financial information of our finance system for 6 years in accordance with our legal obligations.
2.2.6 Categories of personal data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name of the NMO president, vice president, secretary general, treasurer and EFOMP delegates
Name of the Company responsible
Name of the Individual Associate Member
Email Address
Name of the NMO/Company
Home/work/office Address
Professional Information
Membership Information
Membership History
Membership Application Form & Supporting Documents
Membership Invoices and Payment information
2.2.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.2.7.1 With EFOMP emailing list
We add your name and preferred email address to EFOMP emailing list, so that we can send you the EFOMP announcements; newsletters; updates; details of up-coming meetings, conferences, events , EFOMP school editions (ESMPE), and EFOMP examinations (EEB) that you might be interested in; and details of services that we think you might be interested in.
2.2.7.2 With EFOMP IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT providers and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.3 EFOMP Officers/ESMPE board members/EEB assessors
2.3.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point where you apply to be an Officer where we will collect the data from you directly. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.3.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to enable us you to fulfil your duties of an Officer.
2.3.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your information under the legal requirement for processing for current Officers and under legitimate interest for former Officers
2.3.4 Legitimate Interest
We keep details of former Officers for historical purposes.
2.3.5 Data retention period
We will keep an electronic record of your personal details on our database in perpetuity to keep a history of EFOMP.
2.3.6 Categories of personal data
Personal Details
Name
Profile photo
Name of NMO
CV
Home Address
Work Address
2.3.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.3.7.1 With Companies House
We share you details with Companies House so that we can meet our legal requirements.
2.3.7.2 With EFOMP emailing list
We add your name and preferred email address to the EFOMP emailing list in order to exchange information related to your duties of an Officer.
2.3.7.3 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.4 EFOMP Working Group, Special Interest Group and Committee Members
2.4.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point of application where we will collect the data from you directly. You have the opportunity to add to this base data, by contacting the chair of an EFOMP advisory committee or the EFOMP Secretary General through your NMO. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.4.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to:
To arrange committee meetings
To circulate committee agendas, papers, minutes and progress reports
To keep a history of EFOMP’s committee members
2.4.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your personal data under the legitimate interest basis for processing.
2.4.4 Legitimate Interest
Committee members expect this this processing to take place so that they can achieve the objectives of the committee.
2.4.5 Data retention period
We will keep an electronic record of your committee term in perpetuity on our Database, this is to retain the history of EFOMP. In addition we will keep committee agendas, papers and minutes will be kept in accordance with the data retention policy for that committee.
2.4.6 Categories of personal data
Personal Details
Name
Email Address
Name of NMO
Telephone number
Work place
Committee Information
Committee Name
Committee Role
Term of Office
Committee Application Form and Supporting Documents
Committee Agenda, Papers and Minutes
2.4.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.4.7.1 With other Members
We share you email contact details and the committee minutes with other members on the same committee. In some case we may share you name with all members, so that they know who is working on EFOMP committee on their behalf. In addition committee minutes may be shared with other EFOMP committees as required.
2.4.7.2 With EFOMP emailing list
We add your name and preferred email address to the emailing list, so that you can receive committee agendas, papers, minutes, progress reports and arrange committee meetings.
2.4.7.3 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.4.7.4 With Members of the Public and partner organisations
We share your name, organisation and location with members of the public and partner organisations if the output of the working group is a report, book, guidance or any other attributable printed matter.
2.5 EFOMP External Representatives
2.5.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point of application where we will collect the data from you directly. You have the opportunity to add to this base data, by contacting the EFOMP Secretary General. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.5.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to:
To keep a history of EFOMP’s External Representatives
To pay expenses
2.5.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your personal data under the legitimate interest basis for processing, except financial data, which is processed under the legal basis for processing
2.5.4 Legitimate Interest
External representatives expect this processing to take place so that they can achieve the objectives of the external group and have their expenses paid by EFOMP.
2.5.5 Data retention period
We will keep an electronic record of your external representation for EFOMP in perpetuity, for historical purposes.
We keep a copy of any reports that you have submitted in accordance with our document retention policy.
We will also keep your expense claims and a record of your financial history (expenses paid) on our finance system for 6 years in accordance with our legal obligations.
2.5.6 Categories of personal data
Personal Details
Name
Email address
Name of NMO
Role
Term of Office
Expense Payments
External Representatives Information
Reports to EFOMP Committees on progress
Details of external group
Details of expense claims
2.5.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.5.7.1 With the External Group and partner organisations
We share your email address with members of the external groups and partner organisations so that they can send you details of meetings, agendas, papers and minutes.
2.5.7.2 With the EFOMP Board Members
We share your reports with EFOMP board members
2.5.7.3 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.6 EFOMP Newsletter Subscribers (European Medical Physics News)
2.6.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point of application where we will collect the data from you directly. You have the opportunity to add to this base data, by using our website portal. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us, including but not limited to the annual renewal process.
2.6.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to:
To administer your application for a newsletter subscription.
To send you/provide the newsletter regarding EFOMP’s activities and items of interest
2.6.3 Legal Basis for processing
We process your personal data under the legitimate interest basis for processing. Subscribers expect this processing to take place so that they can receive the newsletters.
2.6.4 Data Retention period
We will keep a record of your personal details and registration on our website database while you remain an EMPnews subscriber until we have no longer a legal basis for processing this data.
2.6.5 Consent
You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. You may unsubscribe from our newsletters by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of our e-mails
2.6.6 Categories of Personal Data
The categories of personal data that we process are:
Subscription History.
Subscription Application form
Name
Email Address
Institution
Country
Professional Information
2.6.7 Who we share your data with
2.6.7.1 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.6.8 Legal basis for processing
We process your information under the consent basis for processing.
2.7 People who contact us by Email
2.7.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point of your email to us where we will collect the data from you directly. You have the opportunity to add to this base data, by contacting the office. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.7.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to:
To respond to your email
2.7.3 Legal Basis for processing
We process your information under the legitimate interest basis for processing.
2.7.4 Legitimate Interest
People who send email expect this processing to take place so that they can have a response to their email.
2.7.5 Data Retention period
We will keep the email correspondence until the subject of the email has been addressed by us and for no longer than 3 years.
2.7.6 Categories of Personal Data
Name
Email address.
Contents of your email and our responses.
2.7.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes
2.7.7.1 With our Contributors
We may share the contents of your emails with one or more Contributor such as Committee, WIG, SIG, ESMPE, and EEB board members so that we can provide the best response we can to your email.
2.7.7.2 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service
2.8 People who book on an EFOMP Event (Congress/School/Examinations)
2.8.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point where you book on an Event (congress/school editions/examinations) and we will collect the data from you directly via website portal. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.8.2 Using your personal information
Personal information which you supply will be used to:
To administer your attendance at an Event
To provide other delegates and exhibitors a delegate list, if you consent to this
To send you details of future Events
To process payments for your Registration
2.8.3 Legal Basis for processing
We process your information, with the exception of financial information and marketing information under the legitimate interest basis for processing, since delegates will expect this processing to take place so that they can attend the Event.
We will process your financial information under the Legal basis for processing; and Marketing information will be provided under the consent basis for processing
2.8.4 Legitimate Interest
People who book on an EFOMP Event expect this processing to take place so that they can receive information about the event.
2.8.5 Data Retention period
We will keep an electronic record of your booking, invoices and payment records on our database for 2 years; until we have no longer a legal basis for processing this data.
We will also keep your invoices and payment records on our finance system for 6 years in accordance with our legal obligations
2.8.6 Categories of Personal Data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name
Nationality
Work Place
Name of Employer
Employer Address
Home Email Address
Work Email Address
Date of Birth
Gender
Professional Information
Interest Information
Photo (s)
Conference Information
Name of Event
Dates of Event
Dietary Requirements
Access Requirements
Payment Information
2.8.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.8.7.1 With our Exhibitors and other Delegates
We will provide our exhibitors and delegates with a list of delegates, including; name, city if you consent to this.
2.8.8 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.8.8.1 With the General Public
We share limited personal data (name, job title, name of NMO, the name and date of the event, photos) via the EFOMP website and other communications and publications channels (social media, newsletter).
2.9 People who are an Invited Contributor at an EFOMP Event (ECMP,ESMPE,EEB)
2.9.1 How we will collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point you either contact us or we first contact you regarding invitation to an Event (European Congress of Medical Physics, EFOMP School for Medical Physics Experts, EFOMP Examination Board) either as a speaker or an assessor and we will collect the data from you directly. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.9.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used:
To administer your attendance at the event
To market the event
To pay expenses
To share knowledge
2.9.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your personal information, with the exception of financial information under the legitimate interest basis for processing.
We will process your financial information under the Legal basis for processing
2.9.4 Legitimate Interest
People who participate at an EFOMP Event expect this this processing to take place so that they can receive information about the event and share their knowledge.
2.9.5 Data retention period
We will keep your personal details in the form of speaker abstracts, contributor biographies and copies of the event program in perpetuity.
We will also keep your expense claims and a record of your financial history (payments) on our finance system for 6 years in accordance with our legal obligations.
2.9.6 Categories of personal data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name
Nationality
Work Address
Home Email Address
Work Email Address
Name of Employer
Employer Address
Date of Birth
Gender
Professional Information
Interest Information
Photo (s)
Speaker Details
Title of lecture
Name of Event
Date of Event
Abstract
Copy of Presentation
Video recording of Presentation
Speaker Biography
Copy of Programme
Dietary requirements
2.9.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes
2.9.7.1 With the Exhibitors and Delegates
We will share limited personal data (your name and your abstract) with exhibitors and delegates via the event pack and on our website
2.9.7.2 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.9.7.3 With the General Public
We share limited personal data (name, job title, employer, photos) via the EFOMP website and other communications and publications channels (social media, newsletter).
2.10 People who apply for EFOMP awards and grants
2.10.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point where you apply for an award or grant, where we will collect the data from you directly. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.10.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used
To communicate with you regarding the grant/award
To pay grants and awards
To pay any expenses
2.10.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your information, with the exception of financial information under the legitimate interest basis for processing.
We will process your financial information under the Legal basis for processing
2.10.4 Legitimate Interest
People who apply for EFOMP grants/awards expect this processing to take place so that they can tell people about their award/grant.
2.10.5 Data retention period
We will keep an electronic copy of your application until the award decision has been made. If you are successful we will keep the application until both parties have completed their obligations regarding the award, in addition we will keep limited information your name, the year of the award and the name of the award in perpetuity.
We will keep minimum details of your grant/award on our database/website in perpetuity as this forms part of the history of EFOMP.
We will also keep your expense claims and grant /award payments and a record of your financial history (payments) on our finance system for 6 years in accordance with our legal obligations.
2.10.6 Categories of personal data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name
Name of NMO
Home Email Address
Work Email Address
Name of Employer
Employer Address
Date of Birth
2.10.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.10.7.1 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.10.7.2 With the General Public
We share limited personal data (name, job title, employer, name of the NMO, the name and date of the grant/award, photos) via the EFOMP website and other communications and publications channels (social media, newsletter).
2.11 People who provide images and photographs
2.11.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point where you agree to provide an image or photograph. We also update this data through your subsequent contact with us.
2.11.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information (images/photographs) which you supply will be used
To create EFOMP materials (e.g. posters, leaflets)
To promote EFOMP via EFOMP’s media - Newsletter, Website or social networks
To promote EFOMP via other media.
2.11.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your information under the consent basis for processing.
2.11.4 Consent
You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
2.11.5 Data retention period
We will keep your image while this remains useful to EFOMP, unless you withdraw your consent.
2.11.6 Categories of personal data
We will keep the following categories of personal data:
Personal Details
Name
Email Address
Image Details
The Image
Date of Image
Date of Consent
2.11.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.11.7.1 With third party to Promote EFOMP
We share some of your data (images) with other organisations (Free of charge) to promote EFOMP.
2.11.7.2 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
2.12 Professional Contacts
2.12.1 How we collect your data
We collect data about you in a variety of ways, starting at the point you either first contact us or we first contact you regarding a professional collaboration.
2.12.2 Purposes of the processing
Personal information which you supply will be used to enable us you to contact you about our collaboration.
2.12.3 Legal basis for processing
We process your information under the legitimate interest basis for processing your data
2.12.4 Legitimate Interest
Professional Contacts expect us to keep their data so that we can contact them regarding current or new professional collaborations.
2.12.5 Data retention period
We will keep an electronic record of you while we have a relationship with you + 3 years.
2.12.6 Categories of personal data
Personal Details
Name
Name of NMO
Work Address
Work Email Address
Name of Employer
Employer Address
2.12.7 Who we share your data with
We share some of your data with other organisations and individuals who process data on EFOMP’s behalf (Data Processors). The use of the data we share is strictly limited, by contract, to those purposes.
2.12.7.1 With our IT Software & IT Support Service Providers
We share your personal data that we hold with our IT and IT support Service Providers to ensure that you get the best possible service.
3 How we will keep your data safe
We take appropriate security measures, including to ensure that we keep your information secure, accurate and up to date, and that we only keep it for as long as is reasonable and necessary.
4 Cross-border data transfers
Information that EFOMP collects may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which EFOMP operates to enable the use of the information in accordance with this privacy policy.
You agree to such cross-border transfers of personal information.
5 Updating this statement
EFOMP may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this website.
You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are familiar with any changes.
6 Other websites
This website contains links to other websites.
EFOMP is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party.
7 About cookies
This website uses cookies. By using this website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to EFOMP's use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.
Cookies are files sent by web servers to web browsers, and stored by the web browsers.
The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables a web server to identify and track web browsers.
There are two main kinds of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser, whereas persistent cookies remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach their expiry date.
8 Cookies on our website
EFOMP uses the following cookies on this website, for the following purposes:
gather statistics of visits in this website
Save its users time on this website
Personalise a user's experience of this website.
9 Google cookies
EFOMP uses Google Analytics to analyse the use of this website. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the website. Google will store and use this information. Google's privacy policy is available at: http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html.
10 Refusing cookies
Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies.
In Internet Explorer, you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector.
In Firefox, you can adjust your cookies settings by clicking “Tools”, “Options” and “Privacy”.
Blocking cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of some websites.
11 Contact EFOMP
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or EFOMP’s handling of your personal information, please write:
by email to EFOMP Secretary General secretary@efomp.org or to EFOMP Internet Manager webmaster@efomp.org
by post to:
EFOMP
Fairmount House
230 Tadcaster Road
York YO24 1ES, UK
12 Changes to this privacy notice
This notice was last updated on the 1st February 2020.
EFOMP may amend this privacy notice from time to time to keep it up-to-date or to comply with legal requirements without any prior notice to you.
Where EFOMP discloses your personal information to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obligated to use that personal information in accordance with the terms of this privacy statement.
In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere above, EFOMP may disclose your personal information to the extent that it is required to do so by law, in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise or defend its legal rights.
Share with
